# Andrés Iglesias





https://www.linkedin.com/pub/andr%C3%A9s-iglesias/52/857/316

Software Engineer with more than 5 years of experience in the full Software Development Lifecycle. I'm particularly interested in the development of web and mobile applications. Also interested in agile, front end development, open data and accessibility.

### TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Languages: Java (JEE, JSF, Servlets, JSP), SQL, PL/SQL, JAVASCRIPT, HTML, CSS, RUBY, PYTHON, OBJECTIVE-C, VISUAL BASIC . NET., C#, CoffeScript
- Databases: Oracle (9, 11), MySQL, PostgreSQL 9, SQLite3, MongoDB
- Application/Web Servers: GlassFish (3, 4), Oracle Application Server, Heroku
- IDE: Eclipse, Netbeans, Xcode, Android Studio
- Frameworks: Ruby on Rails (3, 4), JSF (1.2, 2), Bootstrap 3 (Front-end), Node.js
- SDK: iOS SDK 8, Android SDK
- Version control & Automation tools: SVN, GIT, Maven
- Other tools: SoapUI

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## ServiceFrame, Dublin, Ireland

Aug.2015-Present

# Full Stack Developer

Currently working as a Full Stack Developer using technologies such as C#, CoffeeScript, Node.js and MongoDB.

# Central Bank of Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay

Feb.2014-Aug.2015

## Software Engineer

The job consisted of requirement analysis, design, development and testing of internal and external applications.

# Central Bank of Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay

Apr.2011-Feb.2014

#### Consultant

The job involved developing web applications using Java technologies such as JSF and support for users of those applications.

## Alterante, Montevideo, Uruguay

Jul.2013-Jan.2014

## Software / OA Developer

Worked for a Silicon Valley based company developing and testing a personal cloud application using Java language.

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

Universidad Católica del Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay Graduate Teaching Assistant
Systems Simulation Mar.2015-Present

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

CambiosUY

iOS and Android app

Dec.2014

App Store (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cambiosuy/id951769669?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cambiosuy/id951769669?mt=8</a>)

Google Play (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.andresiglesias.cambiosuy)

App for checking the latest currency exchange rates in Uruguay.

Reciclalo May.2014

Rails Web app (http://www.reciclalo.com)

Website for finding recycling centers in Uruguay. All the information is added by the users as well as open data sources. Developed in Ruby on Rails.

# **EDUCATION**

Universidad Católica del Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay *Computer Engineer* 

2008-2012

## PROFESSIONAL LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

**Certified ScrumMaster** 

Dec.2012-Present

Scrum Alliance

Certificate in Advanced English

Jul.2012

University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations